inside the country it is to rebuild in a more
внутри страны она перестроить в более
convenient form for itself as if so well
такую удобную для себя форму как бы так
I at the everyday level I don't know how it is
ну я на бытовом уровне я не знаю как там
higher up at the everyday level everything has become more
повыше на бытовом уровне всё стало
convenient and better such more convenient better yes yes
удобнее и лучше такое удобнее лучше да
what has become better for them at this level
да что стало у ними лучше на этом уровне
and people have a lot of
а у людей появилось много работы
highly paid work that is like this
высокооплачиваемой то есть вот такое
Pan
Пан
Andrey what are you like today I see you
Андрей какой вы сегодня я вижу вы
have changed your clothes you also look just like this
переоделись вы тоже смотрю прямо такой
I often change clothes You had your signature signature look
весь Я часто переодеваюсь У вас был ваш
was yes
фирменный фирменный вид был да
yes pa Andriy
да па Андрий
question Trump didn't want to be a man of
вопрос Трамп не захотел быть еть маном
Ukraine where
Украины где харчева
will you have food Britain will help
будете Британия поможет
Europe I don't know what Trump wanted didn't
Европа не знаю что Трамп захотел не
want but for now weapons are being supplied to
захотел но пока оружие поставляют
Ukraine Yes these ones won't be able to handle it either it seems like
Украине Да этих тоже не потянут вроде
such we'll
как такое
see I see that Russia can't yet
посмотрим Я смотрю что Россия пока не
recapture Sudzha Therefore for now everything is
может суджу отвоевать Поэтому пока всё
fine
нормально
Yes I will say this if with the way we have been
Да я скажу так если с тем как нас за 3
pumped up with
года накачали
weapons and missiles in 3 years which didn't exist 3
оружием и ракетами которых не было 3
years ago when you stood near Kiev and
года назад когда вы стояли под Киевом и
wanted to take it in 3 days but now
хотели взять его за 3 дня но теперь
We have so much of everything and drones already and our
Столько у нас всякого есть и дрона уже и
own drones
свои дроны
Dato
Дато
Tatarstan
Татарстане
Basta yushchie  factories What is it
Баста ющие заводы Да что
I know one thing I understand that it is not profitable for America to
такое Я знаю одно Я понимаю что Америке
do so that Russia
э делать так чтобы Россия что-то
gets something from this in America very well
получила от этого в Америке очень хорошо
Russia is killing its military-industrial
Россия убивает свой военно-промышленный
potential Russia is under sanctions
потенциал Россия лежит в санкциях
cut off from
отрезанная от
Europe there is nowhere to
Европы газ некуда
sell gas there is nowhere to sell goods
продавать товары некуда продавать
Russia is completely dependent
Россия полностью зависима
[music] it has
[музыка]
become and will continue to be like this on you
стала и так будет дальше на вас повесили
you took 70 li ards according to Mr.
вы взяли 70 ли ардов со слов Пана
Zelensky But they told you that you owe
Зеленского Но вам сказали что вы должны
170 Well 100 were lost somewhere they are demanding 500
170 Ну 100 потеряли где-то требуют 500
What kind of mathematics is this
Это что за математика такая
at all no well can you explain the logic of these people I
вообще нет ну логику этих людей можете
have no idea they will
обяснить понятия не имею
just give us another 100
просто нам ещё нам ещё дадут 100
billion because 1 billion invested in Ukraine
млрд потому что вложенные в Украину 1
causes
млрд наносит экономике Российской
10 pdo damage to the economy of the Russian Federation that is America
Федерации 10 рдо ущерба то есть Америка
investing 1 billion is killing the
вкладывая 1 млрд убивает экономику
Russian economy by 10 billion quite an effective
России на 10 млрд довольно эффективно
investment Well if America will
вложение Ну если Америка будет
agree on something with Russia if if
договариваться о чём-то с Россией если
yes Koby mushrooms grew in his mouth
если бы да Кобы во рту выросли грибы
let's do this when America agrees on something
давайте так вот когда Америка о чём-то
with Russia then you
так и договорится с Россией тогда вы
will come out and say  Mr. Andriy, look,
выйдете и скажете Пан Андрий смотрите
there is a signed paper. And while all this is
есть подписанная бумага А пока это всё
written with a pitchfork on water. Mr. Andriy, you are
вилами по воде писано Пан Андрей вы
more knowledgeable. These were questions. These are
более подкован эти это были вопросы это
not some of these. I don’t know, so these
не какие-то эти Я не знаю поэтому это
were answers. These were answers. It is
были ответы это были ответы только что
clear that there are no more
понятно и что нет больше
questions. I will never ask you. I have a
вопросов я к вам никогда у меня есть
question. How much did the Russian economy lose
вопрос Сколько экономика России потеряла
from this war and how will you
от этой войны и как вы будете
replenish it within the country. Rebuild it
восполнять внутри страны она перестроить
into a more convenient form for yourself. As for
в более такую удобную для себя форму как
me, at the everyday level, I don’t know.
Я на бытовом уровне я не знаю как повыше
At the everyday level, the Armed Forces have become more convenient and
на бытовом уровне ВС стало удобнее и
better. More convenient. Better. Yes,
лучше удобне лучше
what has become at the best
да что стало лу
level? People have a lot of
уровне у людей появилось много работы
highly paid work. That is, this is
высокооплачиваемой то есть вот такое
true. There is no one to work. People do not want to work
правда работать некому люди не хотят
highly paid work. If the markets,
высокооплачиваемой работы Если рынки
on the contrary,
наоборот
collapse, people in furniture, there, in
схлопнуть у людей в мебели там в
some moments, in products, all this has
каких-то моментах в продуктах там это
become valued there and people have begun to do
всё стало цениться и люди стали сами
it for themselves. Well, not for themselves. And how would
себе это делать ну не себе А как бы на
those small production facilities be sold now,
продажу те небольшие производства сейчас
such rather large, more or less
такие довольно крупные более-менее
enterprises? I understand that you have begun to
предприятия Я понимаю что вы стали
produce cars instead of imported ones,
выпускать и автомобили вместо импортных
for example, we cost telephones.
например телефонами стоим
No, there is no such thing. Yes, you know,
Не Да такого нет нету такого Да знаете у
I have such a feeling. Then they took on
меня такое ощущение тогда взялись
high-paying jobs well, I
высокооплачиваемые работы ну я по тому
understand from where I live that the
месту где я живу я так понимаю что
machines appeared from somewhere,
откуда-то появились э станки откуда-то
customers appeared from somewhere, but somehow we have
появились заказчики но у нас как-то есть
furniture production there,
мебельные производства там
knitwear, these people are developing, it’s
трикотажные Эти люди развиваются вот так
interesting
интересно
if less money began to come into the country,
если денег в страну стало приходить
much less, because Russia
меньше намного меньше потому что Россия
began to trade less with other
стала меньше торговать с другими
countries, does not sell gas, oil, and so
странами не продаёт газ нефть и так
on, yes, then where is there more money in the middle of the country,
дальше да то откуда в середине страны
where I can’t tell Andrey, where is
откуда я не могу сказать па Андрею вот
this from, but I know for sure that the thief, well,
этого откуда но я знаю точно что вору ну
I’m talking about a low level where I
это я говорю о низком уровне там где я
use some of these, here I’m talking
пользуюсь какими-то этими Вот я говорю
only about that area of ​​the economy, and how much,
только о той сфере экономики А сколько
yes, how much, is the salary of a teacher
Да Сколько сколько зарплата учительницы
in your
в вашем
city
городе
80,000, what
80.000 это какой
city is this? It’s a small town, Labinsk,
город Это небольшой город Лабинск
Labinsk now,
Лабинск сейчас
yes, so the city r.ru writes the salary of a
Да так вот город r.ru пишет зарплата
teacher in Labinsk for the twenty-fifth year, the
учителя в Лабинске за двадцать пятый год
average salary of a teacher in Labinsk for the
средняя зарплата учителя Лабинске за
fifth year is
вать пй год
25.61
25.61
rubles, here are the vacancies in Labinsk, a teacher of
руб вот вакансии в Лабинске учитель
Russian language and literature from 22,000
русского языка и литературы от 22.000
rubles to 27,000
руб до 27.000
rubles, you’re a little off  about 80 It
руб что-то вы немножко сли про 80 Мне
seems to me, sir Pan Andrey, in our communication with you there is
кажется сударь Пан Андрей в нашем с вами
never deception Well, let's
общении нет обмана никогда Ну давайте
go Come in Look, I just typed in Yes, the
Зайдите Посмотрите вот я прямо вбил Да
salary of a teacher in Labinsk and 8 is
зарплата учителя Лабинск и 8 нет
gone my conversation with the teacher at school the day before yesterday
помине мой позавчерашний разговор с
8 stop pppppp No, you're probably
8 стоп пппппп Нет вы наверное путаете
a little confused not how much he received per month
немножко не сколько он получил за месяц
And how much is the salary for the rate because
А сколько зарплата за ставку потому что
he could work at d and a half rate
он мог работать на д с половиной ставки
That is, like 2 and a half of the teacher's work, it's
То есть как 2 с половино работы учителя
true and then get a little
правда и получать тогда немножко
more
побольше
answered you there was a conversation I heard correctly
ответил вам был разговор я что услышал
correctly So I also look
правильно правильно Так я ещё смотри
if a teacher receives, for example, 27,000
если учитель получает например 27.000
rubles two rates - this already turns out to be
руб две ставки - это уже получается
54,000
54.000
rubles if a person receives 30,000 rubles Well,
руб если человек получает 30.000 руб ну
look, I'm taking vacancies Yes, a vacancy, a
вот я смотрите я беру вакансии Да
vacancy for a teacher in
вакансия вакансия учителя
Labinsk right now we
Лабинск прямо сейчас
are opening so a
открываем так
teacher's job in Labinsk 16 vacancies 10
работа учитель Лабинский 16 вакансий 10
vacancies
вакансий
so a
так учитель
chemistry teacher at the secondary school named after Four-time Hero of the
химии СОШ имени Четырежды героя
Soviet Union Georgy Konstantin is there
Советского Союза Георгия константи есть
such a thing Yes,
такое Да у
you have it like that I don't know here from  25,000 rubles to
вас так не знаю вот от 25000 руб до
40,000 rubles so a teacher of Russian language and
40.000 руб так учитель русского языка и
literature also has a hero of the Soviet
литературы тоже име геро Советского
Union Russian Lite from
Союза рус Лите от
21,000 to
21000 до
36,000
36.000
so a history teacher of the same school 22,000
так учитель истории той же школа 22.000
to
до
27,000 in the ninth school Russian language is
27.000 в девятой школе русский язык
more expensive in the ninth school by 27,000
дороже в девятой школе на 27.000
looking for a teacher a mathematics teacher in the
ищет преподавателя учитель математики в
fourth school from 22,000 to 30 you
четвёртой школе от 22.000 до 30 даже
can even get like this a
можно получить так
teacher of criminology in the
преподаватель по криминалистике в
Kuban economic and philosophical
кубанском экономическо-философские
teacher of English in
преподаватель английского языка в
college 230
колледже 230
bucks can you find me at least one
баксов можете мне найти хоть одну
vacancy in Labinsk Yes, where a teacher is
вакансию в Лабинске Да где учителю
offered more than p
больше п предлагают
thousand and salaries lower than 60 600 bucks
тысяч анд зарплат ниже чем 60 600 баксов
or 800 we don’t have people won’t go to
или 800 у нас нет люди не пойдут на
work e times e times I know they will go go
работу е раз е раз я знаю пойдут идут
otva that’s why there is not a single vacancy all
отва вот и нет ни одной вакансии все
vacancies are there yes here is 40,000 maximum
вакансии есть да вот 40.000 максимум
I see you say below  60 won't go and
вижу вы говорите ниже 60 не пойдут а
who do these
кого же находят эти
schools find I can't say I don't know where you're
школы не могу сказать я не знаю где вы
looking and what you're looking at Well here's the
смотрите и что вы смотрите Ну вот сайт
Google site I'm typing here gorodrabota
Google набираю вот городработ
Labinsk
Лабинск
so lank so school
так ланк так школа
2 so teacher psychologist 25 30 rubles history and
2 так педаг психолог 25 30 руб история и
social studies seventh school
обществознания седьмая школа
22,000 rubles where is this Lapinsk
22000 руб где этот вообще лапинск
located
находится
damn Krasnodar
блин Краснодарский
Krai seems to be not a poor region how are
край вроде не бедный регион как такие
there such salaries at all
зарплаты там вообще так
maybe
может
no aunt Seta school 20-30 ssya
нет тети Сета школа 20-30 сся
rubles January 30 d fifth year Well that's it
руб 30 января д пятого года Ну всё
Show me at least one vacancy Yes
Покажите мне хоть одну вакансию Да
teachers in Labinsk so that there were 50,000 just well
учителя в Лабинске чтоб было 50.000 вот
Come in Look I didn't
просто ну Зайдите Посмотрите я же не
make this up Let me
придумал
understand it like that Well I just talked
так понял Ну просто я вчера разговаривал
to a teacher yesterday
с учителем
what he gets I also
что получает Я тоже у него
asked him somehow like this part-time work is
спросил как-то так подработки это
overtime That is, I didn't specify Well so
переработки То есть я уже не уточнял Ну
look Yes we say so
так смотрите Да мы же говорим
we say how much the
так так мы же говорим о том сколько
salary is If a person works three
зарплата Если человек работает на трёх
jobs he gets three
работах он получает три
salaries
зарплат
true I didn't say teachers have a
правда я негу сказа у учителей
salary formed honestly Well if yes If a
формируется зарплата чес Ну если да Если
person works  two rates he
человек работает две ставки он
uh on the first shift then on the second and so
ээ в первую смену потом Во вторую и так
on there somewhere else on a part-time basis
дальше там ещё где-то на полставки ещё
somewhere else as a result has 60 has no
где-то в результате имеет 60 не имеет
free time at all and dies
вообще свободного времени и дохнет
like here let's say another one is there such for
как здесь допустим другой есть такое за
experience for class
стаж за классность
uh there are some supplements probably so the
ээ там какие-то добавки наверное так
budget is the
бюджет
budget there is probably a base so much And
это же бюджет там вероятно база столько
then it went on and on
А там потом
and maybe it didn't go Yes I'm
пошло пошло и А может и не пошло Да я
looking I'm just looking and there really is
смотрите Я вот просто смотрю и реально
no such vacancy and the average if there is an
такой вакансии нету и средняя если есть
average Yes statistics Well so the average
средняя Да статистика Ну так средняя
average salary Labinsk in general we'll take
средняя зарплата Лабинск вообще возьмём
and the median median
и медианная медианная
so Where is the median in
так Где это медиан в
Labinsk that means it is written uh at
Лабинске вот значит написано э на
large enterprises in
крупных предприятиях в
Labinsk the average salary is
Лабинске средняя зарплата составляет
73,000 rubles and in the budget sphere of Labinsk
73.000 руб и в бюджетной сфере лабинской
nya the salary is 42,000
ня зарплата составляет 42.000
rubles That is, even at some large
руб То есть даже на крупных каких-то
enterprises where there is a cool salary of
предприятиях где там крутая зарплата
72,000 this is the average not even the median
72.000 это средняя даже не медианная
so a nurse in Labinsk
так медицинская сестра в Лабинске
salaries are in the range from 36,000
зарплаты находится в диапазоне от 36.000
rubles to 100 that's
руб до 100 вот и
all in short the economy is growing
всё короче растёт экономика
you  asked I said what I
вы спросили Я сказал то что я кругом
see around somehow more weighty What is
вижу как-то так более такое увесистая То
higher Gas Oil what you say
что выше Газ Нефть то что вы говорите
It is beyond my control I do not really understand
Это мне не подвластно я не очень понимаю
Lido you do not see it Yes icebreaker never
Лидо вы его не видите Да ледокола ни
understood
понял
well So I understood so eh in time
хорошо Значит я так понял э во за время
Russia began to live
сво Россия стала жить
better some part
лучше часть какая-то
middle probably a little probably still the
средняя наверное чуть наверное вс-таки
middle part of the population began to live better Yes I do not
средняя часть населения стала жить лучше
know how the top I do not know how the
Да не знаю как верха не знаю как
marginals Well here is the middle
маргиналы Ну вот средняя
part Well to live well is to have the
часть Ну хорошо жить это иметь
opportunity to earn something or
возможности что-то зарабатывать или
go find a job if a person has an
пойти найти работу вот если человек есть
entrepreneurial streak more
жилка предпринимательская больше
opportunities if there is no such streak it is possible
возможностей если нет такой жилки можно
Okay good prosperity of Russia is such and
Окей хорошо процветание России такое и
further something You are too
дальше что-то Вы слишком
kind such prosperity and further I wish
добры такого процветания и дальше желаю
Yes that there was even more such
Да чтоб ещё больше было такое
prosperity good evening Hello
процветание доброго вечер Здравствуйте
Hello
Здравствуйте
Kilja Will I do not understand I am from Estonia yk I do
киля Будете не понимаю я из Эстонии
not
ык не
understand Russian you understand Russian I understand
понимаю русский понимаете руский понимаю
yes
да
we have Russians in Estonia Russia Moscow
у нас в эстони руски есть Россия Москва
understood and in Moscow Where did you come from to
понял а в Москву Откуда приехали в
Moscow Where did you come from I did
Москву Откуда
not understand to Moscow Where did you come from to Moscow Where did you
приехали не понял в Москву Откуда
come from I was
приехали в Москву Откуда приехали Я
born in Moscow about A  who by
родился в Москве о А кто по
nationality by
национальности по
nationality
национальности
Russian Got it Got it I just
русский Понял Понял Я просто русских
imagined Russians a little differently so I
немножко не так представлял так
imagined it a little like that but a little not
представлял немножко так но немножко не
who do you work as Russian who do you work as Russian I
кем работаете русский кем работаете
didn't understand who do you work as comrade
русский не понял кем работаете товарищ
Russian Head of the
русский Начальник службы
security service of what structure structure
безопасности какой структуры
Auchan store Auchan store you Head of the
Ашан магазине Ашан вы Начальник службы
security service is a rather difficult profession a difficult profession Well ask a different question How many subordinates do you have in the security service comrade
в службе безопасности у вас подчинённых
boss of a person and you command them all
начальник человека и вы всеми ими
manage
командует управляете
Yes to some extent And how old are you and
Да в какой-то мере А сколько Вам лет а
sko T
ско Т
4 is quite young
4 довольно молодо
46 tayur to do this is
46 таюр сделать это
cool and what year were you born
круто а это Вы какого года рождения
what year were you
какого года
born
рождения
1979 to July I 1981
1979 по июля я 1981
really you by the way for 46 years still have a
действительно вы кстати для 46 лет ещё
good appearance young and
нормально сохранились молодо выглядите
how do you
а вы как
feel about
относитесь к операции
Russia's operation in relation to
России по отношению к
Ukraine Yes I myself live in Estonia And I'm
Украине Да я сам живу в Эстонии И мне
scared that Russia can seize
страшно что Россия может захватить
Ukraine and seize Estonia and we
Украину и захватить Эстонию и у нас
will have such and wait wait brother
будут такие а подожди подожди брат
Why are you
Почему
scared 6 years old I can look like
страшно 6 лет могу выглядеть вот так как
you like
вы так как
you I'm scared I don't know what Russia
вы мне страшно Я не знаю что Россия
is doing there products  you may have some not so
делает там продукты у вас может какие-то
medicine super yes Well I want
не такие медицина супер да Ну я я хочу
I'm 43 now 44 this year
Вот мне сейчас 43 44 в этом году будет
Yes I understand that you are 46 and I'm already
Да я понимаю что вам 46 и мне уже
scared to think about this age The main thing is
страшно думать про этот возраст Главное
not to live in Russia at that age at
чтобы не жить в России в таком возрасте
that age that
в таком возрасте
is Russia is not your brother And not even your
то есть Россия вам не брат И даже не
sister
сестра
seriously Well why did Russia build you
серьёзно Ну а почему Россия вам построил
factories factories
заводы фабрики
produced before the destruction of the Soviet
выработали до разрушение Советского
Union Why did they build us factories
Союза Почему
this We
нам построи заводы фабрики это Мы
Ukrainians Estonians Kazakhs all built the
украинцы эстонцы казахи все строили в
oil industry in Russia BAM built Yes we
России нефтянку бам строили Да мы всё
built everything for you and then your Yeltsin and your
вам построили а потом ваш Ельцин и ваш
Gorbachev destroyed everything
Горбачёв всё развалили
took and poured our money
взяли и деньги наши сорни
weeds No do you think that it will be worse
зали Нет вы думаете что хуже будет
if you are part of Russia
если вы будете в составе России
that you
что вас
medicine I don't know I Yes Thank God
медициной Я не знаю я Да Слава богу
health is normal well and When was the
здоровье Нормальное ну а Когда вы
last time you went to the clinic for an examination for example for example
последний раз ходили на обследование в
yes I didn't go a general blood test when you
да я не ходил общий анализ крови когда
took the last
сдавали последний
time 12 days ago and why did you take the test 12
раз 12 дней назад а почему сдавали 12
days ago 12 days
дней назад 12 дней
ago you asked me I answered you 12
назад ты меня спросил я тебе ответил 12
days ago is it at your work or just like that got
дней назад это у вас по работе или так
sick with something got sick with something wasn't sick with anything
заболели чем-то заболели чем-то ничем не
when was the last
болел флюрографию когда делали последний
time they did a fluorography the last time what fluorography when was the last time they did it
раз последний раз чего флюрографию когда
3 months ago I
делали последний раз 3 месяца назад
understood to the dentist when was the last time you
понял к стоматологу когда последний раз
went the last time you went to the
ходили последний раз
dentist I do
ходили стоматолог
n't
я те не
need it I'm just
надо я просто
just about the dental bill It's not a
Просто насчёт ставки зубов Это не
problem to
проблема
do it It's just painful to
сделать Там просто больно вот это вот
put in these implants And I haven't seen it yet with you I
импланты вставлять А я не видел ещ у вас
just asked I asked when the
я просто спросил Я спросил когда анализ
blood test when sta And what's the
крови когда ста А что там у вас с зубами
problem with your teeth I'll say again no I'm not really
проблема Я ещё раз гово не я не реально
I don't see what you have there you don't have you you don't have
я не вижу что у вас там у вас нет вас
teeth upper forehead no teeth And what
зубов верхню челе нет зубов А что
happened 46 years What happened
случилось 46 ле Что случилось
[music]
[музыка]
46 And why did they remove what happened And what
46 А зачем удалили что случилось И что
happened Well
случилось Ну так
it happened like in Auchan there was a fight
получилось это как в Ашане там драка
And they knocked you out or how did they knock you out Or
была И вам выбили или как вам выбили Или
how is it not sha
как это не ша
but how is it
а как
alzhan it was 10 years ago Well it's at
алжан это было 10 лет назад Ну это по
work for a security agency for a security
работе по охранному агентству по охранно
agency no It's not connected with a security
агенству нет Это не связано с охранным
agency listen Well  you have some kind of face
агентством слушайте Ну у вас вот лицо
as if you are not quite
какое-то такое будто бы вы не совсем
Russian where were your grandfather and grandmother
русский откуда ваш дедушка бабушка были
from Ukraine from
из Украины из
Ukraine where were your grandfather and grandmother from where were your
Украины откуда дед с бабой были откуда
grandfather and grandmother from Yes,
дед с бабой
yes,
были родом Да да
grandfather was from Poland Grandmother was from
дедушка Был с Польши Бабушка была с
Ukraine I'm telling you Well, if
Украины Я же говорю Ну у вас вот если
you comb your hair normally, make it look younger
вас нормально причесать омолодить было
Well, it's obvious you have a Cossack type,
Ну видно типаж
Cossack, you are not Russian but because of the fact
казацкий не русская у вас но из-за того
that in Russia What did Russia do to you
что в России Что с вами Россия сделала
Look how Poles live in Poland like
Посмотри как живут поляки в Польше как
Ukrainians in Ukraine Yes, everything is beautiful 46 years old
украинцы в Украине Да все красия 46 лет
young strong with
молодые сильные с
teeth I'll tell you honestly
зубками я те честно скажу
yes You spat on the ground on the
да Ты плюнул на землю на
floor Okay, tell me more Okay,
пол Да окей рассказывай дальше Окей
tell me more I have a
рассказывай дальше У меня
350,000 salary in Russia 3,500 dollars
350.000 зарплата в России 3500 долларов
dollars I will transfer to your what are they called dollars
дол переведу на твои эти как там доллары
dollars Yes,
доллары Да
euros
евро
3,500 Well, 3,500 dollars is a cool
3.500 Ну 3.500 долларов это крутая
salary So listen further So listen
зарплата Так слушай дальше Так слушай
further I live normally
дальше я нормально живу
I bought myself a house by a pond in the
Я купил себе дом у пруда в
Moscow region I swear to you I can
Подмосковье Я тебе клянусь я тебе могу
show you my house by  I have 14 rooms in the
показать свой дом у меня 14 комнат в
house I have three
доме у меня три
apartments 14 rooms in the house 14 rooms in the
квартиры 14 комнат в доме 14 комнат в
house And you live alone in these
доме Да и ты живёшь сам в этих
fourteen rooms rooms alone
четырнадцати комнатах комнатах один
No, not alone with the
Нет не один с
dog Why do you need 14 rooms in the
собакой Зачем тебе 14 комнат в
house the dog's name is
доме собаку зовут
shaitan the dog's name is can you show me your
шайтан собака зовут можешь показать свой
refrigerator what do you have in the refrigerator I
холодильник что у тебя в холодильнике
wonder what What does a person eat who
Интересно что Что кушает человек который
gets 3500 dollars in Russia well that's
получает 3500 долларов в России ну это
stupid I won't
глупость я не буду
show because you don't even have a refrigerator
показывать потому что у тебя нету Даже
refrigerator Look it's
холодильника холодильника Вот смотри так
not working
он нерабочий
[music]
[музыка]
probably a refrigerator I'm telling you again
наверно холодильник я тебе ещё раз
I won't show it means you
говорю я не буду показывать значит бедно
live poorly there is no food Come on, do
живёшь нежи нет еды нет
n't breed it yourself 14 rooms And
Да ну ты сам не разводи 14 комнат А
how many floors do
сколько этажей у
you have three floors that's more than
тебя три этажа это получается Больше чем
rooms per
комнаты на
floor uh
этаж э
I'm telling you seriously
Я тебе серьёзно
show me your house Show me
говорю покажи мне свой дом Покажи мне
your
свой
house Why okay don't show it tell me what do
дом Зачем ладно не показывай скажи как
you think Where do people live better in
ты считаешь Где люди живут лучше в
Russia or in
России или в
[music]
[музыка]
Europe Well I'll tell you honestly Brother I don't
Европе Ну честно тебе скажу Брат я не
know I have a normal job here  I
знаю у меня нормальная работа здесь я
get
получаю
I have three apartments in Moscow I have a house
У меня три квартиры в Москве у меня дом
in the
в
Moscow region So you have a house a three-story
Подмосковье Так у тебя дом трёхэтажный
house in the Moscow region with 14 rooms and three more
дом в Подмосковье на 14 комнат и ещё три
apartments in Moscow yeah yeah Well listen for 46
квартиры в Москве да да Ну слушай для 46
years old it's generally
годов это вообще
Bingo And how did you earn so much as three
Бинго А как ты так заработал аж на три
apartments in Moscow
квартиры в Москве
Moscow to tell you the truth and
Москве тебе правду сказать
you will write it down now and then show it Yes, you're not lying to the ambassador it's
а ты сейчас запишешь и потом покажешь Да
not
послу врёшь не
honest give me your word I give you my word I
честно дай слово даю
squeezed it out how I squeezed it out how I squeezed it out Well it doesn't
слово отжал как отжал как отжал Ну это
matter how And
неважно
like penne
как А типа у пенне
nne No well and who has
нне Нет ну а у кого
[music] drug
[музыка]
addicts drug addicts Well there was such an
наркоманы наркоманы Ну было такой
opportunity you understand
возможность понимаешь
Well
Ну
look here's my house
смотри вот мой дом
look Okay okay I believe about the house Ve I
смотри Да ладно ладно я Вер про дом Ве я
believe about the house ve so as not to go that I just do
Вер про дом ве чтоб не ходить что просто
n't understand well how it was squeezed out How can you squeeze
не понимаю ну как это отжал Как можно
out a house Mot
отжать дом Моть
Well I just bought it for cheap like
Ну просто купил по дешёвки типа кого-то
forced someone to steal it and rewrite it to myself Well yeah
заставил переть переписать на себя е Ну
And why did I make it out for And why did I make it out for Well you
да А за что заставил А за что
understand there are such
заставил Ну понимаешь бывают такие
situations For example I just don't
ситуации Например я просто не
know how
шарю чусь
I bought it  three
Я купил три
apartments
квартиры
house Well there was just one person who
дом Ну просто был один человек который
was pleasing to me
был мне угоден
what he was like what he was
какой он был какой он был неугоден
unpleasing to whom unpleasing to whom
неугоден кому неугоден
you will write this down now then I will give you my
ты это вот сейчас запишешь потом мне
word I gave you my word
слово я тебе дал слово
I did it for my children you understand
я сделал это для своих детей понимаешь
But you do
А у тебя же детей
n't have children I told you that I have
нет я же тебе сказал что у меня в
two children in Uzhgorod in Uzhgorod yes So
Ужгороде двое детей в Ужгороде у да Так
you are a Muscovite I
ты же Москвич мо
lived for years I was born in
жил Я родился в
Moscow And how are the children now They don't worry
Москве А как сейчас дети не Переживают
that the war is going on I give
что война идт
them money I am
про я им деньги
forwarding as you are forwarding if with ROSI
Пересылаю как ты пересылаешь если с РОСИ
not x many in
не х много в
Ukraine who helps me I
Украине кто мне помогает Я
[music] I am
[музыка]
forwarding and to the children How old are the children from
Пересылаю а детям Сколько лет детям с
years if you are 46 I didn't understand to the children How
лет если тебе 46 не понял детям Сколько
old are the children in Uzhgorod How old are the children in
лет в Ужгороде детям Сколько лет в
Uzhgorod 1211
Ужгороде 1211
is how they were born in the same year
это как они в один год
with an interval of a year in a year
родились с интервалом в год через год
in
через
[music]
[музыка]
year what do you think Why is it fighting in
год как считаешь Почему
I didn't understand what do you think Why is
воюет у не понял как считаешь Почему
Russia fighting with
воюет Россия с
Ukraine And you think it attacked Ukraine
украино А ты счи сю напал на Украину
Ukraine I only
Украину Я только так
think so a  who is to blame for this
считаю а кто виноват в этой
war
войне
and will I be against you or what
я и буду против тебя что
Putin I do not argue not
Путин не спорю не
argue you were in prison you were in prison in prison in prison was sitting in prison did not understand in prison was sitting in prison was
спор ты сидел на зоне ты сидел на зоне
sitting
зоне сидел зоне сидел
No you know Zolkin Yes I saw
Нет ты золкина знаешь золкина Да видел
you saw you can
видел ты с ним можешь меня
introduce me to him I can not tell him directly
свести не могу ему напряму
and I'll run I'll run I'll go on Come on Hello
а Побегу я побегу я дальше
comrade Zolkin here is
Давай Алло товарищ золкин тут
a six year old in short a
шестилетний короче
Muscovite wants to talk to you
Москвич хочет с вами
Yes
поговорить Да
hello Hello
здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вы
Where are you from From Krasnoyarsk Krai from Siberia it's
откуда С Красноярского края с Сибири
funny how are you communicating Krasnoyarsk resident And where are you
прикольно чём общаетесь красноярец
from I'm from
А вы откуда Я из
Podolia pod this is where from where Well it's between
подолья подо это откуда где Ну это между
Volyn and
Волынь и
Nastya I understood I understood World Cup general Riva What are you talking about
настян понял Понял ЧМ общ Рива О чём
here I speak for a Jew
общаетесь тут я говорю за [__]
people were talking there it's
разговаривал люди живут там вот
interesting yes By the way in Krasnoyarsk
интересно да Как кстати в Красноярском
Krai people live in such cold
края люди живут в таком холоде
and Well I live in a village there is
и Ну вот я в деревне
gas in the
живу газ есть в
village I'm in a garage there is gas
деревне я вот в гараже нахожусь газ есть
in the village no
в деревне
we have a coal industry so the
нет у нас блин угольная отрасль так
question is yes Why Russia Why Do we have gas
вопрос да Почему Россия Зачем У нас газ
like this Russia Yes look coal it
так Россия Да смотрите уголь он
pollutes the atmosphere People breathe coal and
загрязняет атмосферу Люди дышат углём да
then The thing is that  why does Europe
потом Дело в том что почему Европа
sell gas to Europe Russia sold it But it
Россия продаёт газ в Европу продавала А
could not supply gas to Krasnoyarsk Krai
в Красноярский край не могла провести
because we have a coal region I
газ потому что у нас угольный регион ещё
repeat once again you are right coal coal is a
раз повторяюсь вы правильно уголь уголь
century normal countries have not been heating with coal for a long time
- это век нормальные страны уже давно
Well if you are an adequate person
топят Ну вот если вы адекватный человек
you should understand if we have coal
вы должны понимать если у нас угольные
mines all around if they are closed and a
разрезы кругом если их закрыть и
gas line is laid What will happen to the
провести нитку газовую Что будет с
people who work in the extraction of rubles
людьми которые на добыче рублей работают
will they be in other areas work in
будут в других сферах работать в
production
производстве
there what kind of b then do I understand correctly
там вот какой б то я правильно понимаю
what I am looking at a person b I understand correctly
что смотрю человек б я правильно понимаю
that you heat with coal in order
что у вас топят углём для того чтобы
not to save people in the mines Yes coal of
людей не сохранять шахт Да угольных
course these are jobs
конечно это рабочие
this is
места это
production Well how is this logical I
производство Ну как это логично всё
understood everything I have on coal Everything I live in the private
понял вот у меня на угле Всё я в частном
sector that is I have my own house I am
секторе живу то есть У меня свой дом Я
now in the garage damn an ​​automatic boiler is
сейчас в гараже блин автоматический котл
standing on coal damn they do
стоит на угле блин
n't even warm my head And the question is Where did you
голову даже не греют А вопрос А куда
fill the Buka everything is super yes And where is the
л Буке засыпал всё супер да А куда
result of burning coal Where is it
результат сжигание угля Куда
thrown into the
выкидывается в
atmosphere Well how carbon dioxide goes into the
атмосферу Ну как углекислый газ уходит в
atmosphere yes yes but there is not only
атмосферу да да но там же не только
look don't stop there is not only
смотрите не стоп там же не только
carbon dioxide in coal these impurities are gray
углекислый газ в угле эти примеси серые
big and so on Yes coal no sulfur
большие и так дальше Да угле нету сер
this is oil hydrocarbons there sulfur
это нефть углеводороды там сера
you don't know chemistry well once again in coal there
вы химию плохо знаете ещё раз в угле как
are just impurities of sulfur No No yes No Yes
раз есть примеси сери Нету Нету да Нету
you have the formula of coal Look and What is the
Есть вы формулу угля Посмотрите и Какая
formula of coal carbon
формула
so it depends on the composition of the coal
угля углерод так это от состава угля
in the main part carbon goes
зависит в основной части углерод идёт
there 50 like you Anthracite let's say
там 50 вот как у вас Антрацит допустим
there 90% here are
там 90% у
impurities What
вот примеси Какие
impurities so impurities 0 these are
примеси так примеси 0 это
impurities what to focus on them now now
примеси на них что акцент делать теперь
look so now look Well come on come on
сейчас смотри так сейчас смотри Ну давай
Google I'm a dilettante then I
давай давай Погугли я блин Дилетант то
know so out of all when I googled the
знает так вот из всех при вот загуглил
sulfur content of coal out of all the impurities
содержание серы угле из всех примесей
that coal can contain sulfur is most often
которые может содержать уголь чаще всего
found sulfur content can
встречается сера содержание серы может
vary from a fraction of a percent to 10-12
варьироваться от доле процента до 10-12
about from the
про от
mass so that's the point a fraction of a
массы так это вот в том-то и дело доля
percent is
процентов это
0 And there if you look at something there is the entire
0 А там если что посмотреть там вся
periodic table Maybe wait like that
таблица Менделеева Может быть так ждать
now so
сейчас так а
look hydrocarbons oil look
посмотри углеводороды нефть посмотри
how much gray is there
сколько там серый
that is sulfur you have there yes and it
то есть серой есть у вас там да и
turns out and you  breathe these sulfurs that
получается и вы дышите этими серны то
is so2 burning sulfur Yes the result is so2
есть so2 сжигание серы Да результат so2
and so3 yes you will have and for so3 this is what
и so3 да у вас будет а у so3 это
well the result when combined with water
что ну результат при соединении с водой
will be H2
будет H2
so4 sulfuric
so4 серная
acid acid Well there 0 this is
кислота кислота Да ну там 0 это
A3 they called This is what so3 - This is such a
А3 назвали Это что so3 - Это такой оксид
sulfur oxide they know so they know no so no there is so2
серы знают so знают нет so нету есть so2
and there is so3 so no How is it no when
и есть so3 so нету Как это нету когда
there is it cannot be because
есть не может быть потому что
valence carbon dioxide so this is so this is
валентности углекислый газ со это со это
not so this is so so sulfur I understood Well okay everything
не со это со со сера понял Ну ладно всё
everything so detant You are just an amateur You do
всё со детант Ты просто Дилетант Ты даже
n’t even know the name of something you open your mouth
не знаешь название что-то открываешь рот
Amateur you should have studied at school Well of
Дилетант в школе надо было учиться Ну
course of course a poor student so
конечно коне конечно двоечник так вот
when you have yes the result the result of
когда у вас есть да результа результатом
burning sulfur Yes you get these
сжигания серы Да получаются вот эти
sulfur oxides Yes which as a result
оксиды серы Да которые в результате Да
Yes the result of burning sulfur Yes there are oxides
результатом сжигания серы Да есть оксиды
no
нет
sulfur and who
серы а серу кто
burns sulfur your coal contains impurities
сжигает у тебя в угле содержатся примеси
including sulfur you said As a
в том числе и сера ты сказал В
result burning se burning sulfur is
результате сжигание се сжигание серы
right then look
правильно то смотри
your coal contains sulfur which
у тебя в угле Да содержится сера которая
burns also together with these other
сжигается также вместе с с этими другими
elements yes As a result of burning this
элементами да В результате сжигания этой
gray these impurities Yes, gray oxides are obtained
серый этих примесей Да получаются оксиды
which are toxic which
серый которые есть токсичными которые
acid rain
кислотные дожди
cause
вызывают
nothing of the Second World War
ничего
kind into the atmosphere is right Yes Well,
ВОВ рода в атмосферу правильно Да Ну
look, you heat your home and you your wife
смотри ты топишь у себя и ты твоя жена
your children breathe these
твои дети дышат этими оксидами
sulfur oxides around us so many forests that this is what
серы вокруг нас столько лесов что вот
I burn it's just a penny
это то что я сжигаю это просто Копеечка
just a drop in the ocean so what does a fox have to do with it You
просто капля в море так причём лиса Вы
breathe right away You look When, for example,
же сразу дышите Ты смотри Когда например
uh, a fire even uh, they do it with smoke you can see how
э костёр даже э делают с дымом видно как
This smoke also spreads
Этот дым распространяется также у тебя
from your house This smoke throughout the village like
из дома Этот дым по всему посёлок типа
goes to lie down Yes, you breathe this
идёт ложиться Да вы дышите этой
0 This is exactly zero tse look if you
0 Вот как раз это ноль це смотри если ты
look at the permissible norms in the atmosphere
посмотришь допустимые нормы в атмосфере
then this tenth when you burn it
то вот этот десятых когда ты сжигаешь он
exceeds the permissible norms in the atmosphere
превышает допустимые нормы в атмосфере У
Everything is fine with us, just fine Well, everything is fine
нас всё хорошо просто хорошо Ну как всё
if you look in Krasnoyarsk they even
хорошо если смотрите в Красноярске даже
introduce a Black Sky regime when they do not
вводят режим Чёрное небо когда не
recommend going outside and
рекомендуют выходить на улицу и
opening a window Yes, I agree yes there is, there is
открывать окно Да согласен да есть есть
this is the result of heating with coal the
это результат топления углём
industry is working yes Well this is the
промышленность работает да Ну это
result  coal heating not only
результат топления углём не только
industry you don't have
промышленность такого нет у вас
industry then no no so not only
промышленности то нету нет так не только
industry all of Krasnoyarsk is
промышленность весь Красноярск
heated by coal all of it But if
отапливается углём весь Да вот если бы
it were heated not by coal but by gas
он отапливаться не углём а газом да
then it would be completely different everything is
тогда бы совсем по-другому было все
heated by coal So I'm saying yes for some reason for some
углём отапливают Так я же говорю да
reason yes you as a region Yes it's been
почему-то почему-то да вы как регион Да
heated since the 15th century Well of course I got it now which one
отапливает XV века Ну конечно понял
damn Some of the uh big people
блин Некоторые из ээ больших людей за
asked for 500 rubles for puddles damn oh-oh-oh
лужи попросили 500 рдв блин ой-ой-ой
Look That is you now Yes you are now
Смотри То есть ты сейчас Да ты сейчас
sitting breathing sulfur oxides your children yes
сидишь дышишь оксидами серы твои дети да
they will develop cancer from these
у них рак будет развиваться от этих
sulfur oxides Yes this is the destruction of the
оксидов серы Да это уничтожение
respiratory tract Yes there are
дыхательных путей Да дисфункции
different dysfunctions of the body yes And you think something that they
организма разные да А ты что-то думаешь
told you from overseas yes
что там из-за океана тебе сказали да у
everything is fine with me So where is everything fine
меня всё хорошо Так где ж всё хорошо
if you breathe sulfur oxides children Okay
если ты дышишь оксидами серы дети Ладно
if you but your little children breathe
если бы ты но детки твои маленькие дышат
sulfur oxides your wife breathes sulfur oxides and her
оксидами серы жена дышит оксидами серы и
chest with sulfur oxides Yes  with sulfuric
грудью с оксидами серы Да с серной
acid feeds children feeds children they
кислотой кормит деток кормит деток они
already secrete carcinogenic substances Yes,
уже канцерогенные вещества у них
in short, in this before our
выделяются Да прямо короче в этом на
eyes you this is an irrelevant question in the
глазах ты это это вопрос неактуальный в
village Well, how irrelevant Yes, look
деревне Ну как неактуальный Да смотри
What is the average standard of living in the
Какая средний уровень жизни в
Krasnoyarsk
Красноярском
Territory Well, look, I'm average, this is
крае ну посмотри я средняя это
life expectancy Here in Russia it is
длительность жизни Вот в России она
small In Russia it is less than in
маленькая в России она меньше чем в
Europe and in the USA Why Because there is no
Европе и в США Почему Потому что там не
And you, you look at Ukraine, wait So what are
А ты ты по Украине посмотри подожди Так
you talking about Ukraine, look, what are you starting to tell me about Ukraine
что ты про Украину смотри что ты мне про
Yes, you are sitting in the world Yes,
Украину начинаешь да ты сидишь в мира да
and instead of admitting that you
и вместо того чтобы признать что ты
live in the world and there is no need to attack
живёшь в мира и не надо нападать на
another country But you need to get out of this one in
другую страну А надо вылазить из этой в
which you are starting What is there in
которой ты ты начинаешь Что там на
Ukraine Everything was just fine with us
Украине У нас как раз всё было хорошо
Until you attacked us Yes, you are
Пока вы на нас не напали Да вы страна
just a country, the European Union Yes, a rich
просто вот Европейский союз Да богатая
country We want to be friends with them And what should we be
страна Мы хотим с ними дружить А что с
friends with you Well, really, what should we be friends with
вами дружить Ну реально что с
you I didn't turn off the sound for you No, I didn't turn off the sound for you, you turned it
вами я тебе не выключал звук Нет я тебе
off Why did you do that,
не выключал звук это ты выключил Почему
you turned it off, you don't hear
ты так ты выключил вообще не слышишь
me at all, I hear you I just  I
меня вообще я слышу тебя Я просто
ignore Because you just understand
игнорирую Потому что ты просто понимаешь
I'll say I'll say it this way What are you Do you
я скажу я скажу таким образом Да что ты
really breathe These sulfur oxides
Да реально дышишь У этими оксидами серы
your children breathe sulfur oxides they die and
детки твои дышат оксидами серы умирают и
you don't want to live like the
ты не хочешь жить так как живёт
European Union Why do you know anyone there
Европейский союз Да зачем вы там кого-то
in Siberia they're dying there and they're dying
знаешь в Сибири дохнут там ну и дохнут
Who's counting you there But instead of
Да кто вас там считает Да но ты вместо
saying damn guys I'd
того чтобы сказать блин ребята Я бы
like to be in the European Union too so that
хотел в Европейский союз тоже чтобы у
we could have standards like the European
нас были стандарты как в Европейском
Union you're sitting you even smoke at home Damn
союзе ты сидишь ты же даже дома куришь
I live on earth Damn I have my
Да я блин вот на земле живу Блин у меня
own house Damn that's where my house is you're
свой дом Блин вот у меня та где дом ты
some kind of security guard you're a security guard somewhere in
какой-то охранник ты охранник где-то в
some institution you're not in your home
каком-то учреждении ты не в своём доме
I'm
мне
24 How old are you How old are you How old are you I'm
24 Ско сколько тебе лет Сколько тебе лет
a little over fifty
Сколько тебе лет Мне за полтинник слегка
Show that this is your house you'll come up with something you're
Покажи что это твой дом ты придумаешь ты
sitting in some medical institution That's obvious You
сидишь Вот это видно
see the work mess You're somewhere a
О видишь рабочий беспорядок Ты где-то
hundred You're standing at the work machine Show behind the
сто Ты на рабой аппарат стои Покажи за
doors that this is your yard You're at
дверями что это твой двор Это ты на
work  somewhere Here is a car everything everything You
работе где-то Вот автомобиль всё всё Ты
you are at a car service station working everything What is this
ты на автосервисе рабочий всё Какой это
your house what are you talking about this is a car
твой дом что ты рассказываешь это
service station it is obvious that this is a car service station Show me
автосервис видно что автосервис Покажи
Come out Show me that this is yours Show me the yard
Выйди Покажи что это твой Покажи двор
Show me that this is a yard yard Show me that this is your yard
Покажи что это двор двор Покажи что это
and not a car service station I can
твой двор а не автосервис я могу свет
only turn on the light in the yard and show me show me Show me Come on so that I
только включить во дворе и покажи покажи
can see that you will
Покажи Давай чтобы я увидел что ты
apologize to me come on yes if this is
извинишься передо мной давай да если это
if you are not a car service station worker This is your
если ты не работник автосервиса Это твой
house then I will apologize come on because you are
дом тогда извинюсь давай потому что ты
lying just oh damn the
обманываешь просто ой блин
door the door Hey what are you you are afraid to open
дверь дверь Э что ты ты боишься открыть
Open the door Wait a
Открой дверь Да
minute Because you won't see with the light like this you see the windows what are the windows
погоди Потому что так со светом не
damn Hello you didn't
увидишь видишь окна что окна блин Алло
say the doors you will open the doors but
ты двери не ты говорил двери откроешь а
what is there through the window you can't see Why did you
что через окно там не видно Зачем ты
turn off the
выключи
light Open the doors open the doors
свет Открой двери открой двери
Uvi Well, fully fully Open the doors Well, fully so that you can see Well you see there is an
Уви
L there
видно Ну вот видишь там Л стоит б
fully Yes fully
полностью Да полностью
Open it
Открой на
all the way I will open it Well from that side Open it Well
всю открою Ну с той стороны Открой Ну
how Damn I will open it for you Damn yes you see
как Блин я тебе открою Блин да видишь
this is a workshop this is not a yard  Everything you
это мастерская это не двор Всё чее
see there is a house, yes, it is not clear, this is a house, this is a car service, this is a car service, everything is a yard, there is no yard, there is a car service, this is a
видишь там дом это да непонятно это дом
car service, you are so poor, car service Listen,
автосервис вы так бедно автосервис
you are a car
Слушай ты работник автосервиса ты
service worker, you are a car service worker, you also turned off the light
работник автосервиса ещё свет выключил
so that it would not be visible how it is there, Yes, in the
чтобы не было видно как там Да в
car service, damn it, you turned it on, Well, show me,
автосервисе блин включил Ну покажи Вот
Now, show me on the door, Yes, show me on the door,
теперь покажи на двери Да покажи на
Turn on the door there, Turn on the door that way, that's all, Open it, Now,
двери Поверни на двери туда Поверни на
open the door, don't Open the door with the light, but the door is open, the door is open,
открыта дверь
you
открыта ты
and Listen, if you run according to my
и Слушай если ты бегаешь по моим
instructions, to
указаниям к
them, in this regard, Well, damn, I am
из в этом плане Ну блин я-то
human,
по-человечески
but
а
[laughter] you
[смех]
lead the last without salt, without solid,
ведёшь послед без соли без солида
of course, you ate, of course, yes, of course, How many times have you
доедали конечно да коне Сколько раз ты
run?
бегал
You didn't
Ты же двор не
show the yard, look. Well, if you fell for
показал смотри Ну если ты повёлся короче
such a scam, in short, yes, then you,
да на такий развод то ты
in short, I lost my cool.
короче я те
Agree, I fooled you by your beauty,
нулась Согласись я тебя по красоте
just by your beauty. Yes, you even
развёл просто по красоте Да тебе аж
felt ashamed, yes,
стыдно стало да
yes,
да
tatatata taratatata, oh-oh, what are you all like, let's
тататата таратата ай-ай Какие вы все
run  ran opened the door ran turned
давай побежал побежал открыл дверь
on the light ran turned off the
побежал включил свет побежал выключил
light now now are you listening Yes,
свет сейчас сейчас слушаешь Слушаюсь
yes, Ukrainian now I'll dry it in front of you
Слушаюсь украинец сейчас я перед тобой
show I want to prove to you that I have a
высушу показать я хочу доказать тебе что
house I want to prove that
у меня есть дом я хочу доказать что у
I have a yard I'll turn on the light oh Ukrainian
меня есть двор я включу свет о украинец
What kind of people are you, you want to prove something to
Да какие вы вы хотите что-то доказать
others Who cares if I
другим Кому какая разница чтобы я тебе
run to you and show you something Yes, really
бегал что-то показывал Да реально
Agree, agree that I ruined you Yes,
льно Согласись согласись что я тебя
chacha And then you sat down so offended Damn,
чача А ты аж потом такой обиженный такой
cool, it was
сел такой Блин
n't me who used to breed checks
да класс не я бывало разводил чеков
that ran three times Yes, but you're stupid,
которые три раза бегали Да но ты тупо
five is more than five, you ran five or seven
пять больше пяти ты пять или или семь
times No, you're really Cool, you
раз бегал Не ты реально Крутой ты так
wanted to prove to me so much that you have a house
хотел мне доказать что у тебя есть дом
That no one has a house for you but
Что у тебя ни у кого нет дома а вот у
in your village in Kra there
тебя в Кра
is a house usually no one in the
в деревне есть дом обычно ни у кого в
village has a house you understand house look
деревне нет дома понимаешь дом смотри
Ukrainian I have a house Look exactly I'll
украинец У меня есть дом Смотри точно я
open the door for you I'll turn on the light I'll
тебе открою двери я включу Свет я
turn off the light But believe me, Ukraine, that
выключу свет Но поверь мне Украине что у
I have a house you wanted to curry
меня есть дом ты хотел выслужиться
favor with me you wanted to prove to me  what yes
передо мной ты хотел мне доказать что да
yes Do you have at least something in this
да Ты хоть как-то что-то имеешь в этой
life That is, you have so little respect for
жизни То есть ты настолько не уважаешь
yourself that you brag about just having a
себя что ты хвастаешься просто наличием
house having a
дома наличием
house Wow you are the only person in the world who
дома Вау ты единственный человек в мире
has a house this is just
у которого есть дом это просто
incredible Damn you are a lucky
невероятно Капец ты счастливчик
millionaire with a house there is a house in the village and
миллионер с домом есть дом в деревне и
even a garage this is just incredible and you are
даже гараж это просто невероятно а ты
all burnt you are burnt burnt yes burnt burnt
всё подгорел ты подгорел подгорел да
burnt show show show
подгорел покажи покажи
Well you see you see you just Look I recorded a
покажи Ну видишь видишь ты просто Смотри
video I recorded a video I will make a
я записал видео Я записал видео я сделаю
cool tiktok out of it cool
из этого классный tiktok классный
YouTube shr cool YouTube video and I
YouTube шр классный YouTube видео и
will show look a Russian has a house he
покажу смотрите у русского есть дом он
wants to prove that he has a house
хочет доказать что у него есть дом
Imagine No one and everyone is like Wow Does a
Прикинь Ни у кого и все такие Вау
man really have his own house and he
Неужели у мужика есть свой дом и он его
will show it through the window
покажет через окошечко Да
Come on I'll leave you And you sit with a
давай я тебя оставляю А ты сиди с
feeling of such humiliation
чувством такого унижения
Come on
Давай
Hello I see in such a rich
Здравствуйте я смотрю в таком богат
man got excited
жи возбудился
grandfather hello
дед здравствуйте
Hello you are at home at the
Здравствуйте вы на
dacha And what do you have there behind the
даче дома А что у вас такой там сзади
house Well I have I
дома Ну так есть у меня
understand I
понял я с
also Well I live alone my wife
тоже Ну один живу жены
no And if I had a wife I would have
нету А если бы была жена то были бы
normal teeth Well yes I understand I see
нормальные зубы Ну да понял я смотрю у
you have a T-shirt So what are you Why are
вас у вас футболка Так а что вы Почему
you wearing such a T-shirt And do you
вы такую футболочку одели А вам зубы
need teeth or a T-shirt Well I just see
нужны или футболку Ну я просто смотрю
that all Russians have some bad
что россияне все с какими-то плохими
teeth I can't understand why Why and
зубами не могу понять почему почему а
Ukrainians are so
Украин соми
good why Ukrainians all have good
хорошими ча украинцы все с хорошими
teeth Russians with T-shirts Wagner all have no
зубами россияне с футболками Вагнер все
teeth In short, my relatives live
зубов у меня короче родственники живут
in Western Ukraine Yeah Well everyone and also yes
на Западной Украине Угу Ну все и тоже да
in a
в
hut And I know you probably
хибара А я вас знаю наверное
understood Well where are you on the blog Tell me where in a
понял Ну вы блоге где Скажите где в
hut in Western Ukraine your
хибара на Западной Украине живут ваши
relatives live where we have huts there Yes
родственники где у нас есть хибари там
everywhere there are vahiba Well Name a settlement
Да везде вахиба Ну Назовите населённый
with a hut about Neva I understand Understand Well what do
пункт с хибара о Неву понял Поня Хорошо
you
вы кем
do as an operator do you
работаете
know what an operator of a
мае знаете что такое о оператор
machine milking machine is I understand
машинного доения понял
Yes you are a blogger what were you in prison for
да вы же блогер за что
And what did I do as an operator I didn't do as an operator
сидели А причём я сидел я не сидел
Well I understand that you served time you
Ну я так понимаю что вы отсидели у вас
don't look like you were in prison And where are you from
виду не сидел А Вы откуда
yourself Voronezh city Voronezh Voronezh understood
сами Воронеж город Воронеж Воронеж понял
And what do you really do as an operator
А кем работаете
operator Okay, I understand, how much is your salary?
оператором Ладно понял сколько зарплата
[music]
[музыка]
700 dollars, yes, for an operator it's
700 дол да для оператора
a lot, and how do you think you live richly?
много а как вы считаете вы богато живёте
Well,
Ну
average, average, I understand. And why did you put on the T-shirt,
средне средний понял А почему футболку
the enemy? Well,
вра
because I bought it, and why did
одели Ну потому что я её купил а зачем
you buy it? And you can't buy it. Well, come on. No,
купили А ты нельзя купить Ну ка Нет
why? Well, I have to wear something. Well, why do you think you're cool there
почему вот ты там считаешь себя крутым
if you Put on such a T-shirt? Well, you're an
если ты Такую футболку одел Ну там же ты
authoritative person among your friends, then sh.
среди друзей тогда авторитетный шь
No, I just bought the one I
Нет я просто ё купил Какая мне
liked. And why did you like it? Well,
понравилась А почем она тебе понравилась
because I liked it. And
ну потому что понравилась мне нравится А
why do you like it?
чем
Well, because they're all fighting guys
нравится ну потому что они пацаны боевые
there. And why don't you go help? You
там все А почему не пойдёшь помочь ты
seem to be fighting, too. Fighting review, who? I see
тоже вроде боевой смотр
you're fighting. Why don't you find them? You won't
Я вижу ты боевой Почему не найдёшь не
go help them. Fighting
пойдёшь им
I trample chickens like that. Yes,
боевой я таких курей топчу
you're like that. Explain to me why,
как Да ты такая Объясни мне почему вот
seriously, without jokes. Why is it that in Russia
серьёзно без приколов Почему в России
everyone who supports Putin and Wagner has
все кто поддерживает Путина Вагнера все
bad teeth. Why is it difficult to get a
с плохими зубами почему Ну сложно
jaw in
сделать себе челюсть в
Russia. And in Ukraine it's cheaper. I'm
России А у вас в Украине дешевле стоит Я
asking why we, Ukraine is poor. We
спрашиваю почему мы Украина бедная мы
we are poor a poor country that
бедна мы бедная страна на которая напала
Russia attacked and you are rich oil gas gold
Россия А вы богатая нефть газ золото
diamonds Why there are no teeth I will tell you about myself Yes
алмазы Почему нет зубов я про себя
tell me in short teeth everything
расскажи вот короче зубы все
I am fed up And
мне достало А
why Well I don't know why they
почему Ну не знаю почему
popped out I am too lazy to go somewhere
выскочили мне это лень мне куда-то идти
there to do something this is for me For me it's brutal they will
там что-то делать это мне Для меня жесть
also say steal other teeth for
ещё скажут ещё другие зубы
for me to pull out a tooth
воровать для для меня зуб вырвать
this will be I mean Well for me I can't
это это будет В смысле Ну мне я не могу
pull out a tooth for myself why well it hurts because
вырвать зуб себе почему ну больно потому
now there is anesthesia now this thing you
что так сейчас анестезия сейчас это дело
won't even feel I'm afraid to be
вообще даже не почувствуете Я боюсь если
honest I'm afraid So what is there to be afraid of
честно я боюсь Так а в чём бояться
look they do anesthesia first I'll
смотрите делают анестезии сначала
explain first they apply a cotton swab Yes
объясню сначала ватку прикладывают Да
now they give you an injection you don't even
теперь делают укольчик вы даже не
hear this injection And then they do
слышите этот укольчик А дальше делают
everything Well we don't understand about this it
всё Ну насчёт этого не соображаем мнет
hurts me and When was the last time you were at the
больно а Когда вы последний раз были у
dentist To be
стоматолога Если
honest I don't even remember the last time a
честно я даже не помню последний раз
tooth was stolen and the rest
воровал Зуб а остальные мне сами
popped out for me I got them That's how And what year did you
выскочили я их Вот так А в каком году вы
steal a tooth
воровали зуб
I won't say honestly Well about 10
я не скажу е честно Ну приблизительно 10
years ago
лет назад
20 sech
20 сеча
Wait 25 years ago the rest of them I
Подожди лет 25 назад остальные сами я их
pulled them out myself just like that with my fingers pulled them out
сами вот так вот пальцами вырвал
myself Yes they are
пальцами вырвали сами Да они
already And how old are you now by the way
уже А сколько Вам лет сечас кстати
52 I'm 43 almost the same age Yes the same
52 мне 43 почти ровесники
age 10 years in a row your
Да ровесники на 10 лет чере на де у тебя
teeth will also fall out at nine I
зубы тоже посыпятся на девять у меня в
lost two teeth at 49 and then they all started
49 лет два зуба ушло а потом начали все
falling out one after another I
один за другим сыпаться
understand And how is your diet
понял А питание как у тебя
balanced Well I don't like you Well what I eat I eat even What do you eat well
сбалансированное Ну я тебя не вкуси Ну
all
ну всем
kinds of animals there like pasta
подряд животными там какими макаронами
all Well as for food I have no problems at all
вся Ну насчёт еды у меня проблем нет
everything but how are
никаких всё
you with nutrition I heard that
е а как у вас с питанием Я слышал что
because of the sanctions now you have
из-за санкций теперь у вас продуктов
no food meat
нету мяса
dairy in the refrigerator
молочки холодильнике
dairy meat Well dairy I don't actually
молочка мясо Ну молочку Я вообще-то не
eat any Which means there is none and meat meat there is
ем никакую А значит нету а мясо мясо
meat in bulk show me that there is something meaty
есть мясо навалом покажи что есть что-то
I don't believe you have meat under
мясное я не верю у вас мясо под
sanctions and there is no meat in
санкциями и мяса нету в
Russia well how can I show you Well bring it
России ну а как я покажу Ну принеси
Show me some dumplings or chicken there Well there
Покажи там пельмени или курицу Ну что-то
must be something if there is  Now I'll show you
же должно быть если есть Сейчас покажу
the camera is there, here's
камера есть
the change Here's the chicken, you
вот перемени Вот курица вот пельмени
can see the dumplings Oh, okay, there's dumplings, yes, the
видно О нормально пельмени есть да
chicken is higher Show me higher higher I can't see
курица выше Покажи выше выше Я не вижу
higher lift it up, otherwise this chicken is probably
выше подними а то эта курица какая-то
frozen a long time ago, yeah Well,
замороженная давно наверное да
I'm good, but beef or pork is something
я хорошо а говядина или свинина что-то
normal I do
нормальное Мясо
n't know if there's meat, chicken - That's meat for the
есть не знаю курица - Это мясо для
poor Well
бедных Ну
[music]
[музыка]
yeah Well, I mostly
да Ну я в основном са
eat myself, I
питаюсь ме
fry something there And I can
там пожарить что-то там А могу принести
only bring it, I fried it, I didn't eat anything, show me show me
только пожарил ничего не ел покажи
yeah, now I'll show you I made a polyp
покажи да сейчас покажу полип
Oh, well, on top of it, zhi Well, I don't see I don't see Show me Show me
Ой ну сверху жи А ну не вижу Не вижу
something in not on camera I can't
Покажи Покажи что-то в не в камеру Я не
see higher higher lower lift higher lift higher and
вижу выше выше подни выше подними выше и
a little further Yeah, what kind of fat is this Well, it's gravy, like gravy
чуть-чуть дальше Ага а что это за жир Ну
for potatoes Well,
это подливку типа подливку для картошки
can you use a fork Well, I don't Well, how is it
Да ну а можешь вилкой Ну я не Ну как это
not gravy, how is it my for everything Well, with a
не подливка как её мо за всё ну по
fork Show me with a fork Well, move it so I can
вилкой Покажи вилкой Ну двинь чтобы я
see how it is Liquid, this is se
увидел как она Жижа это се
H
H
now seconds Warm it up, I well, you  whose
сечас секунды Разогрей я ну ты чеь
heated up yes
разогретую да
show you Stream after all no I communicate like that
показать ты Стрим ведь нет Я так общаюсь
you need Stream Well I don't know I think you
тебе нужно Стрим Ну не знаю Я думаю ты
Stream not me just communicate with Russians
Стрим не я просто общаюсь с россиянами
so
так
normally
нормально
but a little bit
но немножко
ruined
разоре
this is you this is gravy you make yes it
это ви это подливку ты делаешь да
turns out culinary Well I do it I'm the
получается кулинарную Ну я делаю я же
same and this is for dumplings so
один же а это для для пельменей так
gravy no for potatoes for potatoes
подливка нет для картошки для картошки
understood Yeah well potatoes pasta and some drinks Do
понял Да ну картошки макарон а напитки
you sell tea coffee like or
какие-то Чай кофе у вас продают типа или
no
уже нету
sugar of course you sell everything Well I saw
сахар конечно всё продаёшь Ну я видел
that I can show coffee show yes show I
что я могу коф показать покажи да покажи
drink coffee Nava
Кофе пью Нава
here's a can of coffee and lift it higher What kind of
вот банка кофе а выше подними Что за
coffee NEF
кофе НЕФ
Oh cool no you ca
О прикольно
n't see you can see Well you can see you can see yes Yes you can
не не видно видно Ну видно видно да Да
see here's a complete ban loves Yes I have
видно вот полная бан лавес Да у меня
a little left there Yeah I got it I got it Dada you can see don't Hang out don't Hang out oh don't Hang out
немножко там осталось Ага понял понял
Oh yeah bring it Yes what else is there damn hangs
Зависай О да принеси Да что ещё
hangs now it's
есть блин зависает зависает сейчас
going to break
оборвётся
I want to see more fat I got it
Я хочу ещё жир
Come on show the
посмотреть понял понял Давай показывай
fat the fat has already melted
жир жир растопил уже
probably a card card Nura Yes I know
наверно чная карта карта Нуры Да знаю
it's very from the
это очень из
world yes yes frying pan Bring
миро да да сковородку Принеси
Ugu hangs I
Угу подвисает
do one living
делаю один жи
Ugu
Угу
So a and can you well you can take a potato on a plate
Так а а можеш ну можешь взять на тарелку
and show how it is poured well it Can you
картошку и показать как оно наливается
pour on the potato take while it is warm take the
возьми пока оно тёплое возьми картошку
potato on a plate and show how this melted fat is poured onto the plate Well exactly on the potato Yes on the
Ну именно на картошку Да на картошку как
potato how it lies sweat Yes I see that it is dripping and how it
а как оно на картошки
looks on the potato Put put the frying pan Bring more
выглядит Постав поставь сковородку
potatoes Yes and pour Boiled potatoes Well take
Принеси картошку ещё Да и полей
bread take a piece of
Картошку сварил Ну хлеб возьми кусок
bread Show how it is on bread on
хлеба Покажи как оно на хлеб на на
something so that
что-нибудь
take boiled dumplings on them
чтобы возьми вареные пельмени на них
pour something take something on which you
что-нибудь возьми что-нибудь на что
can pour this gravy me
можно налить эту подливу ме
[music]
[музыка]
show e yes yes
показ
show take on these dumplings On pour the
покажи возьми на эти пельмени На налей
gravy Show I want to see the gravy on
подливу Покажи Я хочу увидеть подливу на
something on something
чём-то на чём-нибудь подливу
showed
показал
him the gravy from where they
ему изде
also said normally what are you
что тоже нормально говорили что ты
saying are you kidding me
говоришь издеваешься
I've never seen gravy so
Я никогда не видел подливу так
really showed
реально показал
showed Damn you're hanging out somehow
показал Блин ты как-то зависаешь
and listen but they don't sell butter in your country anymore
а слушай а сливочного масла у вас уже не
Yes in
продают Да в
Russia because there was a crisis and they
России потому что там кризис был и
said they don't
сказали что не
sell butter do you have butter
продают сливочная есть сливочное масло
or only margarine
или только маргарин у вас
Show me the butter there is no butter no way no well there is
Покажи сливочное масло сливочное масло
butter well well
есть нету по-любому нету ну сливочная
I don't eat pigs butter
ж я ж не жу поросна сливочная
what is
что есть
butter damn really Yes there is butter I
сливочное блин реально Да есть сливочная
agree damn I admit I
согласен блин признаю
admit Well what you definitely don't have is
признаю Ну а что точно у вас нету это
vegetables and fruits in
овощей и фруктов нету в
Russia you definitely don't buy vegetables yes
России овощи ты точно не покупаешь да
vegetables everything Well what do you have cucumbers
овощей всё Ну что у тебя есть огурцы
tomatoes any vegetables
помидоры что-нибудь из овощей
I'm in the store I have them all I don't eat them I
я в магазине Всё есть их не ем они мне я
eat them and even
ем то и
dumplings I can't
пельмени не
show myself
показать сам
Yes there are no vegetables And we have we have well we have vegetables I'll
ж Да нету овощей А у нас у нас да ну
show you Show me the
овощи есть покажу Покажи
vegetables Yes show me If you're a kid Show me the
овощи Да покажи Если ты пацан Покажи
vegetables we
овощи
communicate normally Well show me there are I want
нормально общаемся Ну покажи есть Я хочу
Well okay and there
Ну хорошо а
are no fruits eggs And what are you  eat at all
есть не А что ты ешь вообще
then don't eat What are you
тогда не ем Что ты
eating
ешь
meat pel
мя пель
mint no vegetables yes
мято нету овощей да
Okay we'll ban
Ладно баним
you everything his sound freezes not dude
тебя всё звук у него зависает не чувак
of course he it feels like he
конечно он такое ощущение что он сам
wanted to show everything himself I don't even
хотел всё показывать Я даже ничего не
say anything he also ran to
говорю он ещё побежал что-то
show something subscribe to y Telegram right
показать подпишись на й Telegram прям
now axis VN
зараз ось ВН
apok this is very and very important YouTube is busy with
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through scargi ORV in your ban and very
нас через скарги ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
many videos are not shown to people at times do not
багато видео не показуе людям вчасно не
show information about streams That is why
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
we Mali operational links are
того щоб ми Мали оперативний звязок
written right now and while there in telegram
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
okm videos there are also interesting and useful
окм видео ще теж цикава и корисна
information and we are obliged to you trimati
информация и мы повинни з вами тримати
constant operational links
постийний оперативный звязок
independently in that chi will show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine letter
YouTube Слава украини пись